Three-d game on xbox a windows you know,
that was powered by direct ax.
So, in a nutshell our goal by adding direct...direct
...was to take the our of direct acts and to add high-quality
drawing and text capabilities such as what you saw in api such as gi plus
and system...drawing so how well did we accomplish cycle well today directed
...use everywhere from mozilla firefox to our own browsers
...project sorry microsoft edge
and even the complete microsoft office suite of productivity apps and,
furthermore every single application that's written on the universal windows platform
html resemble ...powered by directed
...so we think we've been very successful in this regard.
Kleenex we go.
But, as always we knew there were things that we can improve direct
x was designed to support
the most complex and sophisticated applications in the world and similarly the
api surface is also very complex and frankly it takes a very long-time to master.
So, we have many stories on the graphics timor
developers come to us and they say look I get the benefit of direct
...it's going to give me the fastest performance and the highest visual
fidelity but I'm not trying to build the next halo, you know,
I have like a week to finish this application I really don't have the time to
become a graphics expert and wrap-up on direct...just to get my applications
...run and we really didn't have a great story for these developers.
So, it was with stories like these in mind that we set out to build...
Wintry is a...drawing library that combines the our of
direct acts with the ease of use from dot net level api
as and combine them into one api offering for your windows universal apps.
So, as a
to drawing library we can do things such as draw text shapes two-d
geometry images and also many more sophisticated things such as
image affects advanced blending opacity masks and things like that when to the
as part of the universal windows platform and this means that
it will want any device that is running windows ten in addition
we also specifically support windows and windows phone two-point-one.
You can write your wintry app using cplus-plus csharp or any other clr
language and finally you can get...to the today on you get dot org
...targeting a windows eight-point one or windows phone
important project you can actually ship your apple in the store successfully today.
Just as a note for windows ten we're waiting for the updated release of the windows
tennis decay and latest flooded bits before we release
...up-to-date when...version for windows time.
So, I'm going to give you a quick demo of some of the basic functionality that when to
portability provides to give you a better idea of what we're talking about.
what I'm watching here is an application called the wintry example gallery this is a sample up the
...and it showcases some of the api capabilities you get and also some
...scenarios that you can you can accomplish using
when to the and in fact we actually ship this on the windows and windows phone
stores as a proof of concept so if you want you can download and follow along somebody
...all of you guys were like starring your laptops and phones actually just using wintry?
Don't break my heart please?
So, let's...some basic functionality basic shapes such as
lines rectangles.
And, circles so here you can see we're doing some very basic styling
we've color each line with the different color but wintry obviously gives you much
more powerful functionality to control the appearance of geometry so let's take a look at a bit of that.
So, obviously you can control the color and thickness...when
particular for strokes we can change the solve line?
To dashes or dots or combinations of the above
...can also control the appearance of each daschle dot.
Wintry also supports geometry two-d
geometry basically arbitrary complexity so, what you see here I've drawn a bunch of shapes
score circle triangle and the star and,
I've defined...by combining ten different line segments and just for clarity sake I've told
when to the to outlined each shape in some read?
An important thing here is that if I tell...combine these into a single shape object
a single geometry is not just pasting each shape on top of one another and calling it a
it's actually we calculating the mathematical vector definitions so, for example,
if I told only draw the outline.
You can see that we
are not including the lines where the star intersects with the other shapes.
Next we have text so text fundamental is just a
...form of geometry so you can see here that we've stylized it using
a geometry option we have a gradient that goes some read all the way to
green down at the bottom but because of this text we have a lot of
...functionality as well.
For example,
here I've told when to the to draw the layout bounds of every single character that
basically is the positioning and spacing of every character and we can use
this implement functionality such as hit testing or dragged to select as you can see here.
Wintry is fully unicode compliant and
you can properly display your bidirectional or top-down text as you can see here with this
chinese script and once again because it is text you get layout options.
And, finally we have...system demo so this is something that's a little more end-to-end
we're drawing something looks a little fancy on the screen.
Fundamentally what we're doing here we're just loading a bitmap of a
small particle and fine particle and we're creating many instances of that bitmap and then
were blending them together and animated them across the screen.
Okay, so, what kind of scenarios do we think that?
Do we think role really benefit from...to the of course when to
...as a general-purpose drawing api so we really think the skies of limit?
First we have data visualization
on this is if you have tens of thousands of data points you want to render them on-screen or maybe you
have an architectural diagram or some kind of sophisticated technical drawing.
Second are creative apps this
can include a photo editor app maybe a drawing application or to
your casual game you want sophisticated visuals but you don't necessarily need
the full our of a three engine and finally we have custom controls so, for example,
if you're trying to extend example toolkit now
...obviously has very powerful built-in and custom control functionality but later in this
talk you'll see some errors where you may want to go beyond its capabilities and use when today.
Ok, so, by now you should have a decent idea of what...can do.
What you care and this is an important question because as, you know,
there are many excellent graphics api solutions out there both
made my microsoft and by third parties so what makes...to be special?
If you can remember one slide from this presentation let this be
...reasons why we think that wintry is an excellent tool you should consider.
It is super easy-to-use just like all the dot net level api...that, you know, and,
It offers extremely fast performance and it scales the complexity of your visuals.
It as powerful comprehensive to drawing capabilities and it has
some really unique are graphical tricks that we...you can use to make your windows up
really shine on the store and finally by being open-source we can
provide you our developer community with a high-level transparency and flexibility.
So, let's look at ease of use.
We design went to the two-btwo encourage your creativity and to
let-you explore...experiment as you're building...graphics
what this means is you should be able to come up with some kind of really core visual idea in your mind
implement in your code and then iteratively...tweak
and modified things as you come up with new ideas and...do that with minimal friction and frustration.
So, instead of just talking to some slides I think you guys are probably rather see some live coding and,
because I enjoy tempting the demo god's I will applies in the
grand tradition of if you are introductions we're going to build the
...world out using...and I'm going to show you how easy it is to use into the get started to build
...basic graphics and to quickly build-up from there and do some more sophisticated things
so what we have here is a blank csharp universal app universal windows
up project...of time about a couple small things first?
So, for example, you can see that about a couple namespaces I have a few
random number helpers and these will use later in the talk.
And, finally have this cute photo of some penguins.
So, the first thing that you need to know...when you're using...the is that we don't
...in-box with the windows tennis decay...as a new get package and if you've ever use
...get packages before, you know, that adding them to your project is very simple.
Let's go ahead and write click the project greasing
...get packages now for the purposes of this demo I've already installed
wintry which you can see hear from a local
package source but normally you would go to new get dot org to
download it and you can see and are references...
microsoft graphics dot canvas and that's the name space for all of the wintry functionality lives?
So, now we have to get we need some place to draw the content so I'm going to
...and, went to the sorry now that...to...
Before out-of-control we're just going to telecast tells me what namespaces...looking and.
So, graphics dot canvas dot ui downsample.
Now that we have that out of the way let's go ahead and add a canvas control.
So, canvas control is where you...your canvas were usual your content obviously.
Chemists control provides us with an event called...we'll call this
...will raises event whenever...application needs to reach...content...this includes things
...window or maybe the users manipulated some content on the screen
...auto insert handler.
Close that out.
So, we go to our code behind you can see its added the signature for themethod for the event...
Surpasses us...arguments the first one is just the canvas control that
...the event and the second argument is this canvas...arcs.
So, we take chemist...arcs.
Has this number called drawing session and this-is of type canvas drawing session
chemist drawing session class is where most of the basic
rendering functionality that you need is located this includes methods like draw a line or
draw image on our case?
...draw text.
So, we passing here well obviously we need.
...famous...world.
It's asking for position I don't want to put in a vector
...I'm just going to put in to...so this tells us where we want to draw the text
a and finally we need to give it a color so I'm going to give it a predefined color.
there we go and I feel like every time I press compile and stage I have to like sacrifice...go to
the...something so let's keep our fingers crossed it is turning away.
Registering applications we know.
Wow, that's along loading ok dario hello world so the important thing here is that
apart from that boiler plate that we added we have one-line of csharp and one-line
...and can't really get much simpler than that windy makes this kind of simple
startup possible because we handle much of the background functionality and
startup code that you normally need to
write so when I say the point I'm really talking about to those of you who've use direct tax in
...direct x has this philosophy where you are as the developer
and total control over the behavior of the api and the graphics hardware
but on the flipside this means you literally have to write hundreds and hundreds of lines of code to specify the exact
behave you want just to get to say the first triangle drawn on the screen?
So, into this case we know all about these best
practices we also know that in most common use cases you guys are using the exact same
kong pattern again and again so we really can just do that for you.
Ok, so, teller role is interesting all that I think you guys have seen that many
times I personally think just plain black-and-white taxes a little bit boring so,
let's change things up a little bit let's do.
...bunch of...that's...for...zero I remember my for loops.
So, we'll do two hundred operations of this.
I also remote parentheses.
So, we're trying to hundred lines let's give it a random positions we're going to use some of those
hoppers I did random axiom random...give us to.
Random floats.
...instead of having a pre specified color we're going
to use the from a rgb.
Color dot from a rgb helper this let's define a...using
the alpha red-green-blue values from zero to two-fifty five.
Alphas can be fully opaque but for the other three
color the channels we're going to use just a random number.
Okay, one more go in the sacrificial...
The real ok so that's a little more interesting right we have a bunch of
...world sale look a little different once again with the for loop
two lines of csharp one-line example so as I was modifying the
draw text method you might have been wondering what a second like all you're doing is changing the
...color like can I do like size or font like layout like other
advance things the...yes of course we let-you control all of that so
...activate intelligence here you can see we have a lot of over loads for
draw text maybe a little hard to see on the screen but,
for example, this one is more advance...it provides
this last class that you passing called canvas text format in particular that's what you
user control font family font weight things like that.
However, my case I'm just doing whole world I don't really care about fought I just wanted some reasonable
defaults I didn't have...the parameters and...one-two does from...is
...gives me these choices of api...give-me just the right level control
from my scenario so for simple cases like this one the code
should be very simple as I make things more sophisticated in my in my app the api should
scale and complexity as well.
All right so I personally like it when things move around on the screen let's you some animation.
...back into
...example I'm going to replace the canvas...
...animated control.
So, canvas control is designed for mostly static content so this
is typical mainstream app where you don't want to redraw unless something is happy to
invalidate dot content so that's what we did previously.
Chemists animated control on the other hand...designed for continually changing content so this might be like a
to...game or some kind of animation and you want to control to
razed draw event on a regular interval.
So, under the covers canvas animated control
action behaves very differently from canvas control if you use direct...to do this, you know,
that you running on a background thread you have different integration points sample if the change where your
message...works once again because we're wintry we do all this
for you and we can give the developer a very
consistent experience between these different modes of operation so, for example,
canvas...control.
Has a draw that?
And, we'll see it looks basically identical to the normal canvas control draw events.
By default we get drawn sixty times per second that's
every sixteen milliseconds so I don't even need to specify
that what I can literally do I can take my existing...code cut it out.
Plopped in you canvas animated control event handler just delete that.
Let's see what we have.
All right so sixty frames a second we have a lot of drawn animated texoma
...course my one
...kind of looks really weird but two lines of code one-line of markup.
I'm going to one more thing so one of the more advanced functionality that you get from wins tr image
processes of brushes basically something that can paints the interior of
a geometry region so,
for example, when I specify the solid the...in the in this example right now
it's actually creating a solid color brush underneath the covers...image brush
...is just a brush that where you get the content from image that you look from disk?
So, the interest of time I'm going to cheat a little now I'm going
to take some free written code first we have a couple of namespaces.
We're going to.
Add a new events.
...resources.
So, qui resources where we recommend you create your went to the
resources if you notice now we're calling draw sixty times a second so probably doesn't make sense for
you to like...the disk and loaded image and create an image
rushed every frame instead create resources is the place to do that.
And, finally I'm going to...in the prebuilt handler for create resources.
So, what we're doing here?
Canvas image animal control...resources.
But, this one is doing as, you know, loading it resources from
...an asynchronous operation so we're telling wintry when
we are dawn where we are completed loading any asynchronous resources.
And, we call a method that we've defined
load resources asic it's right here and we're just doing two things here.
First were loading the image from disk for creating this thing called the canvas bitmap a number creating
are chemists image brush from that image so now they have the
resources loaded let's changer actual draw code.
So,...a solid color find.
...can put in the image brush.
Because this is a more sophisticated scenario wintry asks us to put
a canvas text format class once again I don't really care.
So, we're just going to talk...one.
All right so that's not too bad what we see here every time we call draw
...you can imagine it acting like a stencil where the penguin image can
pick out from behind and we're doing this
to hundred times per frame sixty frames per second.
And, as before just a few lines of csharp
code one-line example we're able to build this a very quickly and with minimal...
So, what we saw here wintry let-you
right much less code to get your drawing the interesting part because we handle a lot of the heavy lifting
for you and also we give you simple api choices for when you only
want simple functionality and we scale along with the needs of the developer when you want
to more advanced things?
So, next...performance so what is easy-to-use what happens if
it's not fast enough to keep up with my needs spoiler.
We are very fast.
So, them through that by showing you.
Oops sorry.
...show you a modified version of our whole world
application...today so we're drawing rectangles instead of sr instead of
...texture so you can kinda see the visual difference more withdrawing five hundred of these
...squares every frame.
...important to know that we can actually go much faster than this
we're drawing at sixteen milliseconds per frame that sixty frames a second
but running on this little surface pro three and this is a handy little
...little...made by the from the guys at the...garage
...of the screen but this is just a regular surface per three is very light-weight you know,
battery life optimized...sixty frames per second and in fact the surface
...threes lcd screen as with most laptops is limited to
sixteen milliseconds per update sixty frames per second so windows actually doesn't allow us to
render any faster because really makes no visual difference so because
when the graphics team we like more our let's crank up the number of...calls let's bring up
to something truly ridiculous here we get around ten thousand
frames ten thousand draws per frame this is really kind of in a territory...three-d games here
...three-d games and even with this like ridiculous number of...
...please never do this you can see the images basically completely...than just please just
...once and be done with it don't do what I'm doing here but even with this
like stupid scenario we're getting about twenty five a little over twenty five frames per second
it's like two hundred fifty to three hundred-thousand squares draught squares with
little penguin images drawn per second that's pretty good so why you remember that
...fluctuating a little bit so ten thousand draw
calls per frame and maybelike thirty five to forty milliseconds of course the question
is can we do any better if we're going to use native direct...right that's the gold standard.
What I have here?
Are the exact same scenario but we're using direct to the same
...squares?
And, let's go ahead...up to something stupid.
...that something, something ridiculous as you see here with native direct
today were fluctuating and it's a little lower but we're getting
around thirty five frames per second so almost three hundred-thousand squares
drawn per second as before but the important thing to...
According to know first of all performance measurements are always highly,
highly dependent on the scenario that
you're accomplishing and hardware that you're running on this is just one particular micro benchmark
but the message of hope you guys get is that from most common scenarios we do not expect you to
see any significant performance difference between when to the and directory.
...first...probably guessed...built on directory were built one
hundred percent on direct...and specifically focusing as I mention of
beginning of the talk direct two-d and direct right and, as I said before direct
...is the fastest way to do graphics on windows is the foundational
layer of for graphics everything that renders to the screen in windows
every line of text every line uses
directory and direct right now the vertex team with every released
...significant amount of effort to squeeze every last
bit of performance out of that graphics hardware so,
all of this goodness that we baked into the platform you get for free when you use...
So, if you might be wondering...the second simon you mention that
zimmer is also built on direct...so doesn't that also minute super-fast
...yes it's a matter scenario
...was optimized for every day user interface scenarios...
really powerful functionality on top of...drawing these are things like data binding
...declared of animations retain mode layout...a lot of our powerful staff and even then it gives you
a great performance like...typical ui scenarios but let's say you
...doing ten thousand squares with penguins flying around.
...not exactly designed to do that ...the here scales better with those kind
of very intensive graphical operations.
When today
on the other hand we give you easy-to-use treaty rendering and very little else,
for example, we don't give any of those services that I just
mentioned and this lets us focus all of our energy on being a very
...very low overhead layer on top of direct today?
So, we've shown that it's fast and
...is easy-to-use and it scales with your demanding performance requirements but,
I've only...like text and lines and some basic shapes
...does it need all the needs...you have from more sophisticated rendering.
So, just like how I said being built on directed indirect
...gives us very good performance it gives us
a very comprehensive drawing capabilities as
well as I mentioned earlier how everything on windows and,
up to the most complex of apps like office uses direct write...for rendering and,
with wintry we had a philosophy were if it's
exposing dt and it's rendering related we want to have
...wintry exposing directly sorry...running related we want to also habit in
...almost everything you can do indirectly indirect right in
...today.
I want to talk now about three specific areas in when to the that we think are particularly
core and we think that you can use a differentiate your apps on the windows store.
The first is image...
If you're not familiar with these image effects also known as filter
facts and there are graphical transformation that you
...pixel data so here I have three common examples of
discrete transfer morphology and gaussian blur.
So, when...provides a...of over thirty built-in
effects the real our you get with the facts are that you can
combine them together into changing graphs and animate them and realtime?
Let's take a look.
At some effects.
So, go back to the example gallery.
So, here, for example,
...something basic gaussian blur we're just changing the blur radius over time.
Saturation.
Blend is a little more complex it takes to inputs we have all of the
standard ported off of one...composite mods arithmetic composite.
Morphology as we saw before this lets...or thin novel...in your image.
We have some more sophisticated things here's lighting
...actually we're doing is we're using the image of
our intrepid mascot cinnamon and we're extracting.
...basic creating height map based on the luminous...using that to white.
We have something like displacement map displace map and also the lighting effects that you saw
that previous demo are these are actually combinations of multiple effects that we use together
...specifically...for displacement map we're using a transform to the effect
...turbulence effect and displacement map effects.
So, what exactly does that mean when I say we combine multiple effects together?
Effects take inputs and the key thing is that the input to an effect can be an image
such as the source image but also can be another effect such as you see with turbulence which feeds into
to transform which feeds and displacement map so in this case we start with
turbulence and turbulence generates...and noise and that's basically pseudo random noise that
has this kind of smooth appearance and you see this often in like video games and special effects
in movies...map affect takes the bitmap
...that turbulence field and...it to warp the image and you can see in the output we
have the animation by sticking this
...transfer...between turbulence and displacement map and you can imagine that
it's like if I have this ripple pane of glass and from my face so that's the turbulence noise
...viewing the distorted seen...and I kinda just like wrote move the pane of glass
around like this right you can imagine the world in front of you also ripple over time so the
specifics of the scenario aren't that important the and the key take away is that these
effects are powerful on their own but you can combine them together and
...animator properties in real-time to get some really clever visual tricks.
One thing I want to emphasize the
...is that you commonly called...image effects but they can be apply to any
...the content geometry text images or...all the same.
So, we now go to the burning text demo this is something you might have seen if you've attended
a direct to talk in recent years
...can't we...it over this demo this is applying no less than ten
...to give this kind of shivering flame the important thing here is
that this is just tax and we're doing this dynamically in real-time so we can replace this.
For reference to implement this it took about two hundred fifty lines of csharp
...code to do this
and native directory a take something like over sixteen hundred lines cplus-plus.
No, this is not endorsement to apply burning text all your text unless perhaps
actually doing like late nineties heavy metal band up or something
...are not new design guidelines for universal windows apps.
Ok, next for powerful functionality we have direct x interop so we design...to the to give you
guys a comprehensive set of to drawing functionality but we know the most successful
...always pushing the boundaries of what's possible
with our api surface and what we want to avoid is having like a quote-unquote
...garden and this is where if you are doing things that we've designed for an
...api it's easy to...beautiful sunshine rainbow
you'll flowers everywhere but the instant you try to go outside of that be in...like fall
office like...of difficulty views or even worse it's just not k
is just not possible to do what you want using or api so as, you know,
when...is built on top of direct...and source solution to the
wall garden problem is we make it very straightforward for-you to take a
wintry object and extract the underlying direct...object that it's built on and
also vice versa you can take any direct x resource dx gi
...have and you can easily construct the corresponding...to use
...in this way you get access to all of the
...api surface and the
most important thing is that you can leverage your existing direct acts or when to decode
base mixing usage of the other api and you don't need to throw out your existing code?
So, let's show you with a concrete example.
So, we have here...kind of standard
three-d demo of three-d spinning teapot and this is being rendered in direct
...using the excellent direct...toolkit to hubble's
...these things and,...we're doing here one thing that direct three-d doesn't have
...functionality for is rich text
rendering so entail is seeing a layout fonts things like that and
...is we use wintry we've just...some text...elevating up
overtime and we use that as a texture in direct three-d with every frame so
...just mapping it on to the teapot then what we're doing we take the render
target indirect three-day we bring that back into the and we're using
...apply this bloom post-processing effect so bump up the intensity right here?
What hi?
As we see here.
We go from one today...want to go a little further maybe at some
three-d functionality we're going to directory no loss of code.
Or we can start with direct three-d.
If...to take advantage of something that is easy, you know,
affects and, went to the we can also go that way and no loss of code.
Ok, last up for powerful functionality we have integration with video and composition windows
...api is.
Video and composition our to errors that are closely related with...graphics so we
know that you guys will probably want to use these capabilities together.
Even though we into the is not part of the
inbox windows sdk we ship as you get package we've worked closely with
the corresponding platform teams to make sure that you can seamlessly user
...content with video and composition scenarios?
So,...the first api is the new visual layer api which is part of the
windows dot ui dot composition name space this api is an early preview state for
build but, it's basically a lightweight way for you to add animations
and effects manipulations to ui.
One of the most important things that ads is this thing called independent animations if you've ever in html resemble
...before you might have use independent animations these are basically
a way to guarantee that even if you're app even if absent main thread the
...thread is busydoing calculations or rendering graphics...the animations
will continue to be smoothing glitch free and the user any user interactions
salon in your apple still...response to user interactions like stick your finger touch.
We design went to the so that you can take any wintry content and users input into
the visual layer and this means you get the best of both worlds when titties immediate mode
treaty rendering and the composition api...retain mode functionality.
The second api want to talk about is I basic video...in the windows media
...name space.
I basic video
...is a new is a completely new paradigm for processing video and windows
You implement and I basic video fact interface and you can use
that affect to transform any video on the system that includes downloaded videos
on-disk the user streaming from the web or even videos your capturing live
...from a video camera as before we design
...so that I can take captured video frame.
Process it however I like using
...and put that back in the media pipeline so let me show you what I'm talking about.
That's a little, little washed out but you can see me right this is
just a standard webcam app you know,
it's taking live capture video and rendering onto the screen.
But, let's take...to the content and put it on here let's take that displacement map that we looked at earlier.
And,...right.
We can do whatever kind of crazy things we want using
realtime video and while I look really ugly...stop that.
Not very photogenic apparently we think this is a great example
of combining to complimentary api...when to...and video
...and using them to just open up like crazy new scenarios that really
want possible before so one more, for example.
Here I've taken my video...
Chop it up into...little square
tiles and every frame I'm rotating and scaling these tiles right.
Okay, I'm getting a little dizzy...that.
So, how hard was that to do?
The rotated tiles...that last
one you saw including the namespaces and all the boiler plate for the
high basic video affect implementation just under one hundred lines of csharp code
in comparison if you were to use direct to native direct to the
cplus-plus and media foundation so that's the native component that analyzed the media api
...just...do something simple like a gray-scale...over two thousand lines
cplus-plus code one hundred lines versus two thousand now that's
a powerful capabilities that using these windows ten api as can give to you.
...unless we have open-source so open-source is not exactly new thing I microsoft and you
can see over time we have release more things on...licenses we have a dot net
foundation when js and when two-d?
Was we first announce it in the first announced in september of
two thousand fourteen and restarted shipping are first you get packages a couple months later and we're proud that
from day one every single line of code that goes into winter the
has been available on get...under the apache two-point-two license.
So, we think that making
wintry open-source gives you guys to key benefits the first one is that we can
be highly flexible and responsive to-you in fact we push
...new get package...and push new...get hub every single two weeks.
Second we can be highly transparent.
As I said you can browse every single line of source code on get hub are you can build
everything from wintry itself to the documentation to the example gallery
sample...because our tool...one hundred-percent public tooling...
You can even
...you...also know exactly what we plan to do because our backlog is fully public.
So, what when today we want to engage strongly with our developer community what is to be a
two-way conversation why...send comments
our blog if you have any questions or you found blogs and problems we want
to file issues and get hub if you have
bug fixes or chained or your new things you want to add to into the
...submit apache we have a contributor agreement very quick...and, you know,
we want to know what you guys think...what you like tells what's hard
...what kind of scenarios you want to be able to into the we build this api
for you and it really depends on what you guys think about it?
Okay, so, what's next for into the.
First up we want to finish support for the universal windows...this
means is we want to reach the same level of api stability and
future completeness as we have with windows eight-point the windows eight-point one version.
...we want to reach and api stable one-point-zero release for people who don't
want to deal with api breaking changes if you go and you get today you'll see that the
...version is either point seventeen or zero point
...eighteen so we're waiting for waiting for the official windows
are the next windows flight to go up before we pusher next release so we standby the
quality and stability of new of wintry regardless of the version number
...the version number means is that until we declare one-point-zero we want to have the
ability to respond to developer feedback so we're not locking down
or api surface once we reach one-point-zero
...have a...have an api stable one point
...released branch in addition to future parallel development branches
...continue to make breaking changes.
And, the last thing that we're looking to do is to
expose all this new goodness that is com online in windows ten the
...directory team has been very busy adding a lot of new goodies you should go see my colleague
...hudson's talk on friday if you want to learn more and,
today we don't expose any of that even the uw
key version only exposes direct x from...features windows eight-point.
So, we hope to get these all done in the windows ten...timeframe but as always
...completely on feedback from you want to know is this
...priority of things are these even the things that you want to work on.
Okay, so,
I think you guys have a pretty good answer to this question...easy.
...super-fast.
Have some I dropping visual capabilities and we're transparent and responsive?
So, as you guys continue
...continue to the rest...build and start thinking about that next killer windows
...going to write I hope you keep these three points in mind.
When today is direct...for the rest of us
...ease of use that you expect?
With extremely fast performance and some killer drawing capabilities if your building
for windows eight-point one you can ship a
wintry app on the store today and very soon you'll be able to do so for windows ten.
And, finally we want your help input and bringing...to the to the next level.
So, here we have all the resources everything that I talked about in my presentation you
can find here we also related sessions I highly,
highly encourage you if you're interested in either the composition api
...or the video and audio at api to check out these talks.
So, the...of the went
to the team I just want to thank you once again for coming and spend your time here we are really,
really looking for to see what you guys think about this api and what
kind of amazing graphical experiences you can dream up thank you?
So,yeah, if you have any questions we have to...on either side
...and on the dx support the use of
...from nine...or what's the minimal version of...dx.
So, the question was what is the minimum version of direct some...so direct
two-d and directorate are built on direct axle...so,
we...so also if you're
...for the universal windows platform you right against the direct x eleven api so,
what so if you're not familiar direct eleven has this feature called
feature levels and this allows you to use the directs eleven api but the target hardware
that may not be capable of using exposing all the...features so,
for example, phones like if you have a qualcomm chips that liken windows
...most of those are direct text future level ninety-three you so use a directs
...api but there...to just restrict the api feature usage to what the
us chip...support okay thank you of os windows seven no,
we support windows eight one about the you know,
the strategy that we have we really like everyone operate from windows
sevento windows ten okay thank you do you have any plans to add
...like traditional desktop applications because that's our main meat and
we're doing like financial application for need update the
screen very quickly and efficiently and draw lots of text and right now I've been
experiment in doing that but like you cdf sharpen the direct to the library, you know,
and, basically making a texture than rendering that wpf?
Right but, you know,...like it'd be nice library but it was like it's only for the universal
...platform.
Detailed musing all the other libraries we needs.
So, we focused on obviously building utility piece of
work first we should talk this is something we always want to know where you guys are trying to do with your api is well,
if one after the talkative time like we should talk...and state.
Is there an easy examples saving out the results on the canvas to
file that's a good question we offer we have a helper I'm try to remember exactly what the name
is basically...a single step just like load image asic we have a saving energy...and,
you can just say about all...content yes?
You some idea about
...performance person to using readable bitmap...that not reasonable.
Are you...this examples...bitmap, yeah, so,
I'm not I'm not I'm not an expert...field we should you I can try to hook up with
...people but one of the things, for example,
the readable bitmap is fundamentally cpu basically nothing you can access pixels directly so one
of the things you'll notice...to maintain maxim performance you want use
a api that's...for gpu base rendering so, it depends on your scenario but?
Sorry so,...scenario but they are they are slightly different scenarios there are and
...can talk after you want more information thanks.
...one thing before forget yes, please give us feedback.
Free stuff is there any support for things other than graphics
...like password cracking or stuff that uses cheap you
...the cpu so I some is that something like gmmb.
You kind of things share...
it might be possible that's not one of the scenarios that we had in mind for example,
one thing that you might want for gps direct access to pixel or compute
shares in this case
direct tutti so, directly actually does offer way to write to pixel
...or computers but like at this point that's not explosion wintry that's we would love to
...you have some like super idea that like I want to do this but I want csharp high-performance
send us feedback like it'd be really interesting to say program.
Okay, well,
I guess we'll close...early I want to just thank everyone once again on behalf of the
...the team so I will...the windows insider lounge for...our
to ninety minutes after this if you want to talk to your asking more questions you also
...find me tomorrow afternoon in the expert zone the download an expert
...so-if you want-to talk me there also if you want to learn more about the
wintry api and try to play around with it you should how head over to thequick start challenge
...we have a wintry...takes about fifteen to thirty minutes and you can build
and app in...that looks pretty similar to the
...demo that I showed on stage thanks again enjoy the rest...bill.